<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>maintainer on Nathan Chancellor</title>
    <link>https://nathanchance.dev/tags/maintainer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in maintainer on Nathan Chancellor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 21:14:13 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nathanchance.dev/tags/maintainer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>April 2021 ClangBuiltLinux Work</title>
      <link>https://nathanchance.dev/posts/april-2021-cbl-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 21:14:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanchance.dev/posts/april-2021-cbl-work/</guid>
      <description>Another month down! Feels like I just wrote the March 2021 post&amp;hellip; but I suppose that is what happens when your project moves super quickly :)
Linux kernel patches   [PATCH] ACPI / CPPC: Replace cppc_attr with kobj_attribute: I discovered this issue as part of my testing of Sami Tolvanen&amp;rsquo;s Control Flow Integrity series (more on that below). There are probably many more of these lurking because this pattern is hard to spot without runtime testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March 2021 ClangBuiltLinux Work</title>
      <link>https://nathanchance.dev/posts/march-2021-cbl-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 10:25:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanchance.dev/posts/march-2021-cbl-work/</guid>
      <description>Another month, another post about the work that I have done as a kernel/compiler developer! One of the highlights this month is that I got LLVM commit access so I can merge my own patches into LLVM, which I did twice so far.
Linux kernel patches   powerpc/fadump: Mark fadump_calculate_reserve_size as __init: LLVM 13 switched over to the New Pass Manager (NPM), which has impacted some inlining decisions, which in turn exposed some bugs in section annotations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February 2021 ClangBuiltLinux Work</title>
      <link>https://nathanchance.dev/posts/february-2021-cbl-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:01:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanchance.dev/posts/february-2021-cbl-work/</guid>
      <description>As some of you may or may not know by now, I am now employed by the Linux Foundation to help improve Linux security. The primary way that I am doing that is through the work I do for ClangBuiltLinux, of which I am an official maintainer.
Linux kernel patches First and foremost, I am a Linux kernel developer, meaning that I love sending kernel patches. Getting familiar with git send-email and the standard Linux kernel workflow can be difficult but now that I am used to it, I find other things cumbersome.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
