<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nathan Chancellor</title>
    <link>https://nathanchance.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nathan Chancellor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 13:53:23 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nathanchance.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building the WSL 2 kernel with Clang</title>
      <link>https://nathanchance.dev/posts/wsl2-kernel-clang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 13:53:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanchance.dev/posts/wsl2-kernel-clang/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I built a computer for school that I installed Windows 10 Pro on (link to the current specs if you are curious). I was a little bummed about leaving Chrome OS because I was going to lose my local Linux development environment; however, Windows Subsystem for Linux is a thing and it has gotten even better with WSL 2, as it is actually running a Linux kernel so there is full Linux compatibility going forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My projects</title>
      <link>https://nathanchance.dev/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanchance.dev/projects/</guid>
      <description>All of my personal projects can be found on GitHub, here are a few key repositories that I am proud of:
ClangBuiltLinux ClangBuiltLinux is a collaborative organization between several engineers across different companies like Google, Linaro, and IBM to improve building the Linux kernel with the LLVM tools such as clang and lld. I have contributed various fixes to the mainline Linux kernel, helped triage and debug issues on the issue tracker, improved the continuous integration setup through a set of scripts and Docker images, and developed a set of toolchain build scripts for myself and others to use for consistent testing/developing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloads</title>
      <link>https://nathanchance.dev/downloads/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanchance.dev/downloads/</guid>
      <description>I used to host files on this website but I have offloaded them to other services.
Flash Kernel downloads can be found in their individual repos:
 Nexus 6P OnePlus 5 OnePlus 6 Pixel (XL) Pixel 2 (XL)  Note, these are all unmaintained right now so I wouldn&#39;t recommend running them in their current form but it&#39;s your device.
TWRP downloads can be found in the threads that referenced them:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>